Ryan Evans

Phone: (330) 671-1076 | Email: rdevans87@gmail.com | Location: Akron, OH 44319

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanevanscreative/ Professional Portfolio: https://www.ryanevanscodes.com/

GitHub: https://www.github.com/rdevans87/

Summary

Independent web developer with leadership experience and strong technical background supporting a variety of cross-platform software applications. Certified project management professional and recent graduate of the Ohio State University's full stack coding bootcamp. In depth knowledge of Agile principles and software QA testing methods for each phase of the development lifecycle. Ability to communicate effectively and build fast rapport with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.

Technical Skills

- Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+,
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, jQuery, Materialize, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, Mongoose.js
- Technologies: API, JSON, AJAX, DOM, CLI, OOP, ORM, MVC, CRUD, ODM
- Development: Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Agile Project Management,
 Scrum, Kandan, Mobile First, Wireframes, Pseudocode

Projects

PetTrax Web App

GitHub: https://github.com/rdevans87/pettrax

Deployed: https://secret-coast-15963.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A simple app for tracking your pets daily rhythms
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, CLI, Node.js, MySQL, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, Adobe PhotoShop, Bootstrap, Cloudinary, LucidChart, Heroku
- Role: Full-Stack Developer

Weather Dashboard

GitHub: https://github.com/rdevans87/Weather-Dashboard-March-6-2021 **Deployed:** https://rdevans87.github.io/Weather-Dashboard-March-6-2021/

- Summary: App that provides current and future weather forecasts in the United States.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, Moment.js, Restful API
- Role: Front-End Developer

E-Commerce Backend App

GitHub: https://github.com/rdevans87/ORM-ECommerce-BackEnd/ **Deployed:** https://rdevans87.github.io/ORM-ECommerce-BackEnd/

- Summary: Backend of an E-Commerce site using HTTP requests to modify inventory.
- Tools: Node.js, CLI, MySQL, RESTful API, Express.js, Sequelize,
- Role: Back-End Developer

Employment

IMDb.com, an Amazon Company. Customer Service Specialist

08/2019 - 01/2021

Santa Monica, CA

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps using CRM tools and resources.

- · Collaborated with the engineering team to file bug reports, track unresolved tickets, and manage customer relationships.
- · Contributed to self-help knowledge base articles and implemented new support procedures that reduced incoming contacts and ticket resolution times.
- · Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make data-driven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.

Cast & Crew Entertainment Services, LLC. Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst

04/2018 - 08/2019

Burbank, CA

Assisted with product implementation, software QA testing, and technical support for digital payroll products and services: Studio+, Start+ (SAAS)

- · Provided on-site/remote product demonstrations and training sessions to end-users.
- · Tracked bug reports, enhancement requests, and software updates using Agile project management Scrum in Jira.
- · Acted as liaison between senior leadership to communicate software updates and releases to the customer support team.
- · Collaborated with the product manager and engineering team on development of implementation and end-user training.

Final Draft, Inc., subsidiary of Cast & Crew Entertainment, LLC. Sales Support Associate

04/2016 - 04/2018

Burbank, CA

Completion: July, 2021

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- · Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- · Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016) & Final Draft 11 (2018).
- · Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.

Education:

The Ohio State University

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies Completed: August, 201.